# Peter Torr Smith

# web, cloud, API product technologist, developer, analyst, delivery

Wellington

phone: +64-21-451967

NZ Citizen

email: ptorrsmith@gmail.com

web: <a href="mailto:ptorrsmith.com">ptorrsmith.com</a>

github: github.com/ptorrsmith linkedln: linkedin.com/in/ptorrsmith

# **SKILLS BRIEF**

Full-stack > Ruby, Rails > DBs, APIs, Data > Async Jobs, Eventing/Kafka > AWS, Cloud > Git / Github / Gitlab
Javascript/Typescript > React > Node.js / Express > HTML, CSS > Bootstrap > Hubspot APIs

➤ Stripe payments → Architecture → Wireframing / flow / Design / UML → Business & UX Analysis → SaaS

> Project / Programme delivery > Product & Technology ownership, governance > Agile delivery & tooling

#### **OVERVIEW**

I enjoy people and technology, process and product strategy. This could be developing a product or enhancement, configuring a solution, eliciting and reflecting requirements & constraints, helping design great user experiences and application flow, problem analysis and resolution, and helping others learn. I love building, solving, and learning new things, but mostly enjoy working with and helping teams succeed. Coffee?

#### **EXPERIENCE**

Flux Federation - Senior Application, Data and API engineer - Team "Quokkas" June 2023 - current (Full time, 100% remote)

- Ruby on Rails 7, Rspec, Playwright UI testing, MySQL RDS, AWS, Docker
- Async / Background processing with background jobs and event-sourcing (Kafka)
- Features, requirements, technical design, implementation, test coverage, deployments, pairing, mentoring
- Engineer on call, and performance and problem diagnosis, coordination and resolution.
- Highlights: OpenAPI based API development, performance analysis and resolution, Kafka, PlantUML

AskYourTeam - Senior Developer/Engineer

Apr 2022 - May 2023 (Full time, onsite and remote)

- Ruby on Rails 6/7, React, Rspec, Cypress, Postgres RDS/DynamoDB, JSONB, AWS, Infrastructure as Code
- Async / Background processing with Good Job/Lambda
- Feature leading, requirements, technical design, implementation, test coverage, deployments, pairing
- Highlights: Org structure, automated permissions, imports, multi-select demographics, Hubspot Integrations

**Culture Amp** - Analyst Developer Engineer "Performance Camp" - Scalability, Performance, Simplicity Focus Mar **2021** - Feb **2022** (Contract, 100% remote)

- Ruby on Rails, Rspec, AWS & DevOps, Sidekiq/async, React, Typescript, DataDog, BuildKite, RDS/Dynamo
- Uncoupling product areas from monolithic application and architecture (domain extraction). Microservices.
- Addressing technical debt, performance issues and common platform elements/issues across multiple teams
- **Highlights**: Exports via RDS replica, performance enhancements, GDPR compliance. Technical debt and enhancements for UI/UX. Domain Driven Design platform rework. React and Lambda integration, Launch Darkly.

**Resn Digital** - Technical Director - Development, Infrastructure, Integration & Operations Sept **2020** - Jan **2021** (Contract / Freelance)

- Technology investigation and solution design, scoping and sizing pre-sales, pre-development
- Development, Cloud Infrastructure & services admin, deployments and operations
- AWS S3, EC2, CloudFront, ACM, Lambda, Route53, AWS Organizations, IAM, Docker, Git, BitBucket pipelines
- Daily scrums, workflow management and kanban boards. Burn up/down tracking. Remote teams.
- Highlights: Scoping, sizing, architecture for <a href="https://goodmeat.co">https://goodmeat.co</a>, a Vue, ThreeJS & WebGL digital experience

**HireThings.com** - Developer / CTO for application, platform & mobile-first upgrade (.co.nz / .com.au) Feb **2019** - Aug **2020** (Full time)

- Upgrade from Rails 2 to Rails 5. Shift and re-architect onto AWS platform services (Elastic Beanstalk, RDS, Elasticache, S3, Route53, EC2, VPC / Security Groups, SES, IAM, Certs). Mobile-first Bootstrap 4.5 front-end
- Intern mentoring / training, code reviews, approvals and merges

Peter Torr Smith Profile - 2023

Ministry of Social Development IT - Web, Mobile, UX and Agile Technologies Manager May 2011 - Sept 2018 (Contract and full time)

- Business Analyst, Agile PM Ruby on Rails projects primarily. Web Team manager programme and project scoping, costing, delivery. Project pipeline coordinator - getting projects ready, scoped, approved
- RFP evaluation and vendor selection, contracts, liaison. Agile Toolsets Design and Operations SAFe, Atlassian Cloud Jira & Confluence
- Mobile & UX Capability Manager mixing internal and external capabilities. MyMSD, MyStudylink.

**Catalyst IT** - Business analyst / project manager / solution designer & dev / client liaison April **2009** - April **2011** (Full time)

- Client liaison, project scoping and solution design / options, RFPs, pre-sales
- Analyst / PM / co-dev for Drupal CMS, PHP, Moodle, and Ruby on Rails projects
- Facilitation, Testing, client support. TrueNet internal startup: UX & biz flow, web CMS build, logistics
- Development and solution configuration / operations

HireThings.com - Co-founder, CEO, CFO, Developer

April 2006 - May 2009 (Full time)

- Start-up co-founder, team support and HR. Developer, analyst, testing, ops Ruby on Rails / AJAX, UX, Wireframing, process design, solution co-design
- Summer of Tech (was Summer of Code) co-leadership

Intergen - Analyst developer and DBA - Microsoft technologies

April **2004** - April **2006** (Full time)

- Microsoft .Net developer (C#, ASP.net). SQL Server DBA, .Net/SAP API developer
- Onsite and offsite client technical support & development
- Web apps, Web Services, WinForms, Windows Services

eCentric - Analyst, Developer and DBA

Dec 2000 - Nov 2002 (Full time)

- Analyst Developer Delphi / .Net eCargo & dairy waste marketplaces. SQL Server DBA
- Privilege & fun of working alongside founding Trade Me & AMR/Movac teams

Ministry of Agriculture (MAF) Jan 1994 - Sept 2000 (Full time) - Business IT Projects/Ops manager > developer

### **EDUCATION, TRAINING & DEVELOPMENT HIGHLIGHTS**

AWS Developer Associate Certification - DVA-C02 - Udemy, ACloudGuru, self-paced learning 2023

• Covered most AWS services and best practices for developers. Cloud compute and serverless stacks.

**Udemy** - Ruby on Rails Professional - Re-learning Rails **2019** 

- Built ptorrsmith.com from scratch, Rails refresh and prep for HireThings upgrade.
- Rails 5 (now 6), Javascript/JQuery, Bootstrap, PostgreSQL, web-sockets, GIT and Heroku for hosting.

**Enspiral Dev Academy** - *Modern web and mobile development bootcamp* **Aug - Dec 2018** (Full time)

• HTML5, CSS3 & CSS Frameworks, Javascript backend (node.js / Express) and front-end (React / Redux).

Scaled Agile Framework (SAFe) - foundation and in practice, - in-house and online 2016 - 2018

• Enterprise application of SAFe with Jira, Confluence. Formal SAFe training, exams and certification 2017 PRINCE2 & MSP - Managing Successful Programs - Foundation and Professional 2011, 2015

Better Business Cases (BBC) - Training, Enterprise representation, and exam - Foundation 2013

Certified Scrum Master - agile planning, delivery and team support 2011

Microsoft Certified DBA - SQL Server DBA certification 2001 & 2006

**Graduate Diploma - Information Sciences** - Extramural and on-campus studies, Massey University **2001 Bachelor of Commerce,** University of Auckland - Management, Accounting, Economics, Marketing, Finance, Statistics, Business Computing

#### **INTERESTS**

Mobile, smart & connected technologies (IoT)
Economics
Fermentation
Cooking
Roasting coffee
Swimming
Hiking / walks
Global social and tech/bio trends
Campervanning
Meditation, Mindfulness
Predator Free NZ (volunteer)
Helping others learn / mentoring

# **REFERENCES**

On request